– Good afternoon.
My name is Thomas Mayfield. I am joined
here today by my colleagues Fergal O
'Connor on stage and Jeremy Furster in the
audience. We are here representing the
Cardano Foundation, a Swiss-based non-for
-profit, and we've traveled from quite far
and wide. Jeremy has traveled from Taiwan,
Fergal has traveled from Ireland, and
myself has traveled from the United
Kingdom. And we have done so because what
is happening here in the state of Utah is
a paradigm shift in digital identity. And
what we would like to demonstrate for you
today is the art of the possible, the
potential for what some of these things we
have heard of today, such as guardianship,
could look like for your citizens and how
the state could leverage these
technologies. Before we start the demo, I
would just like to say a few words. We
live in a world where our trust in
government technology and our fellow
citizens is eroding every day. I would
testify that every person in this room and
those watching online believe the
protection of children is our most
important societal responsibility. It is
evident that the internet is a powerful
but dangerous place. A place where we do
not know unequivocally who we are
interacting with online. Is it an adult or
a child? Is it a human? or a machine. It
is a genuine person or a predator. There
are numerous statistics available and I
would like to highlight a few given the
time constraints we have today. In 2024,
ChildLight, the Global Child Safety
Institute, reported more than 300 million
children fall victim to online sexual
exploitation and abuse each and every
year. Similar to the tragic story we heard
this morning, there are more than 1300
reports made involving violent online
groups that encourage children to harm
themselves and others. Online games have
become hunting grounds for predators. Some
of the largest being Roblox, Minecraft,
and Fortnite. Roblox self-reported cases
of suspected child sexual exploitation to
the National Center for Missing and
Exploited Children increased dramatically
between 2019 and 2024 from 675 to 24,000
cases. In the first six months of this
year alone, Roblox has reported more than
it reported all of last year. In 2019, a
study of more than 2,000 child Minecraft
players found that nearly 10% had been
asked by another player to meet in real
life. That's almost 200 children and that
was six years ago. This number has grown
exponentially. There have been numerous
attempts to remedy these risks to
children. However, they do not address the
core problems, how we access the internet,
digital content, and the interactions
children are exposed to. Today, you will
witness for the first time in the world
two technologies, key event receipt
infrastructure, commonly referred to as
KERI, and authentic chained data
containers, ACDCs, being leveraged in a
manner that no other technology can
achieve today. Providing open source,
state-endorsed, digital identity wallet
and supporting services designed to return
control back in the hands of parents and
guardians, empowering them to ensure a
safe and and verifiable digital future for
their children and their children's
children. What we'd like to do now is walk
you through a demonstration leveraging
these technologies.
What Fergal is going to be demonstrating
on the left-hand side is a representation
of the state of Utah vital records
platform. What he will be doing here is
issuing a birth certificate. Now, this may
be a manual process conducted by an
administrator. It could be a checkbox in
an existing system that's integrated. It
could be fully automated. But the point
here is that there are certain aspects of
SEDI that must be introduced by the
government and others that fall into the
power of the parents. Fergal is forming a
peer-to-peer channel with the government,
leveraging the mobile wallet of the child
Oliver in today's demonstration. The
parent, Mary, also has established a peer
-to-peer communication. and she will be
requesting the government issue a birth
certificate to her child as well as a
guardianship credential. These are all
ACDC technology.
So what has happened now is a guardianship
credential has been issued to the parent
and a birth certificate has been issued to
Oliver. server. What you can see online
here is the credential contains any amount
of information, including a direct link
potentially to a file system or server. It
can be fully customized based on policy.
And that is the most important aspect.
This is not tech providers dictating what
the state can use. This is technology that
is built based on policy and law. Now that
the birth certificate has been issued and
the guardianship credential has now been
issued to Mary, the mother. And this could
be a multi-signature relationship for both
parents, for example, all capable with
KERI and ACDC technology. Now, Mary will
leverage the family portal. This is all
open source software you are seeing here
today. This could be running in your home
system like a home media center, or it
could be provided by a third party. The
key difference here is these are not like
the centralized systems. The keys
controlling the data reside in the SEDI
wallet in the hand of the parent. They
never leave that platform. They never go
into this system you are seeing.
Everything must be signed and approved at
the edge or from the wallet. So now Mary
has logged into this system. You'll notice
there were no usernames, no passwords.
This is known as passwordless
authentication. And now Mary is presenting
her SEDI credentials to the family portal.
This will allow the portal to determine
what features should be available to her.
In there, you will see a number of things
appearing in the family tree. This is this
chaining characteristic that was just
mentioned behind ACDC credentials. In the
SEDI wallet is not only a credential
dictating the guardian relationship for
Oliver, but also the guardian relationship
to Liam, Liam's father. So this would be a
power of attorney issued by a court, for
example. The idea is to demonstrate that
all of this information can be contained
within a chain of credentials that are
cryptographically built upon one another,
similar to that scenario with the Lego
blocks just presented on screen. So now
the parents are empowered to issue
credentials to delegate authority to their
children, completely removed from the
state. The state has provided the
credential to prove guardianship, but now
the parent has control. Now, Mary will
issue a credential to Oliver and you'll
see there are three scenarios we've
explored here. Social media, streaming
platforms, and gaming consoles. We will
demonstrate a social media credential and
the ability to customize the attributes.
What you can see here initially is a
conversational age rating. This is the
ability for the parent to decide the age
in which they want their children to
interact with. with. Second, you will see
a time constraint. They can set parameters
around when these credentials can be used,
when these platforms can be accessed. And
finally, there is a content rating that
can be set by the parent. You'll see a
checkbox at the bottom that says enable
safe interactions. What this is telling
the system wherever this credential is
presented, that this user can only
interact with other SEDI-endorsed users.
What we're going to do now is issue this
credential. But before I do so, this is
just an example. The policy will dictate
the parameters of this credential, not the
tech providers. So when that is
established, exactly what will go into
this credential, what are those options,
then that will be implemented. They are
fully flexible. What you will see now is
Mary will receive a request because
although it looks like this system is
creating and issuing the credential, it
isn't. It is merely a Lego block to build,
but Mary must sign with the keys that are
stored in her SEDI wallet, her identity
which is contained within, in order to
execute this action. And now what you will
see is the child will receive a prompt in
their phone saying their mother would like
to issue them a credential and they must
also approve this credential in order to
hold it and receive it. So what you see
here is not only holding and issuing, but
also the ability to do decentralized
verification, which is the next step. So
now that Oliver has received a social
media access credential, he can now
register for a new paradigm shift in
social media that we are calling
Socialbook today. You'll notice again
there is no usernames and passwords.
Oliver will log in online with his
delegated authority from his mother in an
ACDC credential into the Socialbook
platform. Oliver will scan this QR code
you see on screen to establish a peer-to
-peer connection with SocialBook. He will
input his email, but you'll notice Oliver
will not be telling the system how old he
is. The state-endorsed digital identity,
which empowered the mother to create a
social media access credential, will
inform the platform cryptographically how
old Oliver is. Oliver will now register
for the platform and will then then log
into the platform using no usernames and
passwords.
Once Oliver has logged into the platform,
we will now start to explore how those
criteria and restrictions that were set by
his parent can be visualized in a system.
What we have done here is we have tagged
the data in this post with a metadata
label indicating the content level of
which this image was. And because the
parent has set that restriction to teen,
he can no longer view that image. If he
wanted to view it, he could request it.
But let's move on now to the chat to
demonstrate how chat now is leveraging
that age restriction. What you will see on
screen here is existing conversations that
are already underway. And you will notice
below there are a number of SEDI tokens
that indicate that these are users that
that have leveraged a SEDI-based
credential to access and register for the
system. And you will see other users that
have red tags there. These fall outside of
the constraints of the age that was set by
the mother. In a scenario where Oliver
would like to talk to Justin, he must
receive approval from his parents. In this
scenario, Mary, in order to do so. This is
creating a shield online that parents can
control for their children children
cryptographically. What we will now do is
we will move on to another example of how
social media can be leveraged. We've had a
couple of conversations with social media
platforms as well as game development
houses. And we were trying to establish a
proof of concept leveraging decentralized
identity. And the very common feedback we
received was decentralizedidentity is too
complex to integrate into gaming. Games
must have centralized servers. The
identity systems must be centralized in
the platform to ensure the game and user
experience is maintained. So although the
concept and the idea behind a centralized
identity is powerful and they understood
the value it could bring, their statement
was you simply cannot integrate this
comprehensive technology. So I set this
task upon my team to do exactly that. So,
what we have done is we have cloned
roadblocks. We are calling it KERI blocks.
We did this in less than two weeks. Just
to give you an understanding of the
timeframe here, we are not game developers
by any means. And what you will see is
Oliver is now going to register and log
into this platform in the exact same way,
leveraging a credential that was issued to
him by his mother in order to play this
game online. And all of those constraints
and restrictions that are embedded inside
the credential will also pertain to his
usage of this game platform. So, Oliver
will join the system and he will begin
gameplay. And there are a number of
elements here I would like to touch upon.
The level of predatory engagement that is
happening in in-game chat is a significant
concern. What you have now demonstrated
today on screen is the ability to have age
verification built into a game This is a
complete KERI and ACDC based chat
integration into KERI blocks. All of these
communications are digitally signed and
the age of the individuals that can
communicate with Oliver must fall within
those constraints that were set in the
credential. Another huge element to in
-game concerns is purchases. Many times
parents will input their credit card
information to purchase something that
time. And what has happened is children
have racked up credit card bills because
that information is in the game. The
children can click on things and purchase
them and mom and dad only find out once
the bill arrives. In the exact same way
that Oliver had to request permission to
speak to someone who was outside of the
age constraints, mom and dad also have to
approve the purchase. Again, this is a
completely new paradigm shift in in-game
purchases and parental controls for
individuals leveraging online systems. The
next one to two minutes of what you're
about to see is the potential future for
the users that are leveraging Roblox.
There are 20 to 40 million users a day
leveraging this system. There is a huge
opportunity here from a commercial
perspective, but there is a huge risk that
can be solved with this technology. Go
ahead. Let's see if the sound works.
Okay. Sound's not working, but that's
okay.
Go ahead. Do it one more time. Okay.
Secure, portable, and self-sovereign.
Using this identity, you can create your
own rules and trusted circles with
cryptographic proof. Set age limits for
your private space. Define your play hours
or grant access only to friends you have
personally approved. In KERI blocks, you
don't just build worlds. You build the
rules that govern them, creating a
provably safe and personalized gaming
experience. Developed by Veridian and
integrated with NotBlocks.online project,
KERI Blocks redefines how we play in a
connected world. So I leave you here with
a thought. To the parents and the
guardians in the audience and viewing
online today. If you could choose from
this safe, secure, friendly gaming
experience for your children, or you can
take a gamble and leverage the systems
that are available today, what choice
would you make? Thank you very much for
your time.